MD ISLAM

💌 md.islam007@rutgers.edu 🚱 mdislam.com 📞 (347) 459 5013 🕻 mdnahian

SUMMARY

Student at Rutgers University studying Computer Science interested in web development, mobile development, and machine learning. Currently have over 3 years of experience in building cross platform applications for clients and have published 8 applications in the Google Play Store.

EDUCATION

Rutgers University

EMPLOYMENT

B.A. Computer Science (Minor: Mathematics) 2018

Paradox Process, Software Developer Intern, New York, New York

Apr 2017 - Jun 2017

- · Created an iOS and Android application to help people register and track user impulses and emotions
- Designed user interface using Sketch and developed using React Native and D3.js
- · Aided in testing, debugging, and publishing to the iTunes App Store and Google Play Store

Rutgers University, Web Developer, GS-LSAMP, Newark, NJ

Sep 2015 - May 2016

- . Lead a team to develop and redesign the GS-LSAMP website
- Created an RSVP feature and an online timesheet with email confirmation using SendGrid API
- Developed website backend using PHP and created a CMS to upload new slides and update content regularly

FBD Distributors Inc., Desktop Support Technician, Maspeth, New York

Aug 2014 - May 2015

- Provided daily technical support and designed, developed, and maintained company website
- · Installed new software per requirements and setup computers for individual staff use
- · Liaised with vendors and purchased supplies

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Java, PHP, JavaScript, Python, MATLAB, C++ WEB TECHNOLOGIES: Flask, Django, Express, Meteor, Laravel, Codelgniter

DATABASES: MySQL, MongoDB, MS SQL

OS/PLATFORMS: Windows Server & Workstation, Linux, Unix

PROJECTS

Bus or Rail

- Developed cross-platform application using React Native to help decide which mode of transportation is the fastest
- . Created web scraper to retrieve all scheduled times from NJTransit website
- . Created cron job to automatically run web scrapper every week and save updated schedule on Firebase

1StepSearch

- . Created a web scraper to grab videos and music from YouTube, classifieds from Craigslist, and images
- . Developed Android application to search and download data using the web scrapper
- · Created REST API using PHP and MySQL

ScreenGif

- . Developed Android application to record and share phone screen as a GIF
- Created editing tool to crop recorded GIFs
- Application installed by 165 users in less than 10 days

AWARDS

1st Place, CUNY Hack

- · Web application using NLP that generates notes by aggregating all notes in the classroom
- · Using IBM Watson Alchemy API to retrieve text context and subject
- · Using Google Drive API to store and retrieve notes

2nd Place, HackNJIT

- · Android app using computer vision and NLP to help people take the right medication
- · Using OpenCV to detect words in a photo and generate a black and white image which is fed into Microsoft Cognitive Services OCR
- Using NLTK to extract the name, description, and usage information from text

3rd Place, HackNY

- · Android app that allows users to buy and sell mobile hotspot data through tethering
- · Initial connection done using peer-to-peer to transfer funds through PayPal API and encrypted password
- · Created REST API using Flask and MongoDB

New York Tech Meetup, Presentor

· Presented Android app, Peer Wifi, to a theater packed with local technologists

ACTIVITIES